[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- Ladies and gentlemen!
- 女士们，先生们！
Behold my wondrous paintings!
看我奇妙的画作！
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Um, excuse me.
Can I have some ketchup?
- 嗯，对不起。
我可以喝点番茄酱吗？
- Hey, look at my art,
you dummies!
- 嘿，看看我的艺术，
你们这些傻瓜！
- Oh!
- 哦！
- I don't know how you talked me
into this art show, SpongeBob,
- 我不知道你是怎么跟我说话的
进入这个艺术展，海绵宝宝，
but I'm shutting this thing down
right now.
但我要关闭这个东西
现在。
- Aw, you can't, Mr. Krabs.
- 哦，你不能，蟹老板。
Wait until Squidward sells
some of his paintings.
等章鱼哥卖了
他的一些画作。
- Buy some important paintings.
- 购买一些重要的画作。
See me expose my exquisite
suffering.
看我暴露我的精致
痛苦。
Hmm.
These fools don't even recognize
唔。
这些傻子根本不认识
the masterworks
in front of their faces.
杰作
当着他们的面。
I'll confront them
with the power of my art.
我会面对他们
用我的艺术的力量。
- Ahh--
- Witness the beauty!
- 啊啊--
- 见证美丽！
- Pah!
- 呸！
- Come on, Larry,
- 来吧，拉里，
get your salad on!
吃沙拉吧！
- Come on, Larry,
get your art on!
- 来吧，拉里，
继续你的艺术吧！
- Oohee!
My eyes!
- 哦嘿！
我的眼睛！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
The pain!
痛苦！
- I want a Kwabby Meal!
- 我想要一顿卡瓦比餐！
- How about some art
to go with that?
- 一些艺术怎么样
去那个？
[horse neighs]
[马嘶声]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [screaming]
Run, baby, run!
奔跑吧，宝贝，奔跑吧！
- That's it! Squidward is
scaring me customers away.
- 就是这样！章鱼哥是
把我的顾客吓跑了。
I'm shutting this art show down.
我要关闭这个艺术展。
He's never gonna
sell his paintings.
他永远不会
卖他的画。
- Sure, he will.
I just bought one.
- 当然，他会的。
我刚买了一个。
- Ah! Holy shrimp.
- 啊！圣虾。
Why would you do that
to yourself?
你为什么要这么做
对你自己？
- What do you mean? I love it.
- 你是什么意思？我喜欢它。
- Ah.
- 啊。
- Mr. Krabs,
Squidward is our friend,
- 蟹老板先生，
章鱼哥是我们的朋友
and his paintings are so cheap.
而且他的画很便宜。
You should buy one
just to be nice.
你应该买一个
只是为了表现得好。
- [coughing]
- [咳嗽]
I'm good.
我很好。
- Nice?
Nice?
- 好的？
好的？
I don't waste my money on nice.
我不会把钱浪费在美好的事情上。
- But think about how valuable
these paintings might become.
- 但想想有多么有价值
这些画可能会成为。
- Valuable?
What do you mean?
- 有价值的？
你是什​​么意思？
- When art gets older,
it usually gets more expensive.
- 当艺术变老时，
它通常会变得更贵。
Squidward's paintings
might be worth millions someday.
章鱼哥的画作
有一天可能价值数百万美元。
- Millions?
- 数百万？
Out of me way!
别挡我的路！
Here!
- Ow.
这里！
- 噢。
- Gimme.
- 给我。
This is mine now!
现在这是我的了！
- Okay, Mr. Krabs!
- 好的，蟹老板！
- [laughing]
Art, art, art, art, art, art.
- [笑]
艺术，艺术，艺术，艺术，艺术，艺术。
Now all I need to do is sit back
现在我需要做的就是坐下来
and watch me art
grow more valuable.
看我的艺术
变得更有价值。
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- I am a very important
art appraiser,
- 我是一个非常重要的人
艺术鉴定师、
and I say this so-called "art"
我说这就是所谓的“艺术”
will never be worth a penny.
永远不会值一分钱。
- Hey, Eugene H. Krabs
does not--
- 嘿，尤金·克拉布斯
不——
[gags]
Lose money.
[笑点]
赔钱。
There must be
something I can do
一定有
我能做的事
to make this art
worth lots more cash.
来创作这门艺术
值更多现金。
- Hmm...
- 唔...
- I sold all my art?
- 我卖掉了所有的艺术品？
This tiny handful of coins
has legitimized me!
这一小把硬币
使我合法化了！
Who wants the autograph
of a real artiste?
谁想要签名
一个真正的艺术家？
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- Well,
- 出色地，
paintings can become
much more valuable
画可以变成
更有价值
when the artist
is not longer with us.
当艺术家
不再和我们在一起了。
You know, out of the picture.
你知道，在照片之外。
[gags]
[笑点]
- Out of the picture, eh?
- 不在画面中，是吗？
I think I could arrange that.
我想我可以安排一下。
- Artist walking--
check me out.
- 艺术家行走--
检查一下我。
- Check this out.
- 看看这个。
Got a delivery for you,
Mr. Squidward.
已经给你送来了，
章鱼哥先生。
- What? You can't be serious.
- 什么？你不可能是认真的。
An artist, such as myself,
should not be subject
一个艺术家，比如我自己，
不应成为主题
to such menial tasks.
去完成这些琐碎的任务。
Aw, don't be menial
to Squidward, Mr. Krabs.
哎哟，别卑鄙啊
致章鱼哥，蟹老板。
I'll take the delivery.
我来取货。
- No.
- 不。
Mr. Squidward is
a real artist now,
章鱼哥先生是
现在是一个真正的艺术家，
and real artists
can handle anything.
和真正的艺术家
可以处理任何事情。
[wind whistling]
[风呼啸]
- The Arctic is so cold.
- 北极太冷了。
[shivering]
[发抖]
Come on, Squidward,
来吧，章鱼哥，
you're a strong artist.
你是一位实力雄厚的艺术家。
You can do it!
你能做到！
Nope.
没有。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[shivering]
[发抖]
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
- Oh, hey, Squidward!
- Ah!
- 哦，嘿，章鱼哥！
- 啊！
SpongeBob,
what are you doing here?
海绵宝宝，
你在这里做什么？
- Just getting some ice.
- 只是拿点冰块。
Fresh!
新鲜的！
[laughs]
Need some help?
[笑]
需要帮助吗？
Oh!
哦！
[humming cheerfully]
[欢快地哼唱]
- Here's your food.
- 这是你的食物。
- Hey, this is cold!
- 嘿，这很冷！
Perfect!
完美的！
[both laughing]
- Dah!
[两人都笑了]
- 啊！
- Eh, we better get you home.
- 呃，我们最好送你回家。
- Hello.
Is this the art appraiser?
- 你好。
这是艺术品鉴定师吗？
Just wanted to let you know
只是想让你知道
that me good, good friend
Squidward is now
我好，好朋友
章鱼哥现在是
out of the pictu--
从图中——
[stammering]
Wha-what the sea horse?
[结巴]
哇什么海马？
Got another delivery for you,
Squidward.
又给你送了一份货
章鱼哥。
And only Squidward!
而且只有章鱼哥！
- Your eyes are so pretty.
- 你的眼睛真漂亮。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- Last...
[blows raspberry]
- 最后...
[吹覆盆子]
Stop...
[blows raspberry]
停止...
[吹覆盆子]
Rock...
[blows raspberry]
摇滚...
[吹覆盆子]
Bottom.
[blows raspberry]
底部。
[吹覆盆子]
- [moaning strangely]
- [奇怪地呻吟]
- [moaning
and blowing raspberries]
- [呻吟
和吹覆盆子]
- 237 Rock Bottom.
- 237 最低点。
Oh, there it is!
哦，就在那里！
Oh, remember, Squidward,
哦，记住，章鱼哥，
real artists
embrace the unknown.
真正的艺术家
拥抱未知。
Uh, is anyone here?
呃，有人在吗？
[blows raspberry]
I've got a delivery
[吹覆盆子]
我有送货
from the Krusty...
[blows raspberry]
来自库斯蒂...
[吹覆盆子]
Krab.
蟹。
[all blowing raspberries]
【都吹树莓】
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
- What are we screaming about?
- 我们在尖叫什么？
- Monsters!
- 怪物！
- They're not monsters,
Squidward,
- 他们不是怪物
章鱼哥，
they're my friends.
他们是我的朋友。
- What...
[blows raspberry]
- 什么...
[吹覆盆子]
Up...
[blows raspberry]
上...
[吹覆盆子]
SpongeBob?
[blows raspberry]
海绵宝宝？
[吹覆盆子]
[all blowing raspberries
and cheering]
[都吹树莓
和欢呼]
- Yes, I am sure
that Mr. Squidward
- 是的，我确定
那个章鱼哥先生
is out of the picture for good.
永远不存在了。
He will be missed.
人们会想念他的。
So come on over
and tell old Krabs
所以过来吧
并告诉老蟹
how much money
me paintings are worth.
多少钱
我的画是值得的。
[laughs]
[笑]
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
[growls]
[咆哮]
Squidward, delivery!
乌贼王，送货！
- Ooh, this tickles.
[laughs]
- 哦，这很痒。
[笑]
- [Mr. Krabs grunts]
- [先生。螃蟹咕哝]
Follow me, Mr. Squidward.
跟我来，章鱼哥先生。
I've got a special delivery
vehicle
我有一份特别的快递
车辆
just for a great artist
like yourself.
只为一位伟大的艺术家
就像你自己一样。
- Well, that's more like it.
- 嗯，这更像是这样。
Finally some respect.
终于有点尊重了。
- Into the rocket you go.
- 进入火箭。
- Ah!
Ooh.
- 啊！
哦。
Wait, why do I need a rocket?
等等，为什么我需要火箭？
Where is this delivery to?
这次送货到哪里？
- Mars.
- 火星。
- Oh, Mars. Well--
- 哦，火星。出色地 -
M-M-M-Mars?
火星？
- Bye, Squidward.
- 再见，章鱼哥。
- [Squidward screaming]
- [章鱼哥尖叫]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
- Delivery from the Krusty Krab.
- 蟹堡王送货。
- [speaking gibberish]
- [胡言乱语]
[all chomping]
[全部咀嚼]
- Hmm.
All this red, so garish.
- 唔。
都是红色的，太艳丽了。
Ah, this dump needs
a true artist's touch.
啊，这个转储需要
真正的艺术家风格。
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
[munching sounds]
[咀嚼声]
- So now that Squidward
definitely,
- 所以现在章鱼哥
绝对，
100% is gone for good--
what a shame--
100%已经消失了——
真可惜——
what do you think
of these here paintings?
你觉得怎么样
这里有这些画吗？
- Well, of course,
they're awful,
- 嗯，当然，
他们太可怕了，
but if the so-called "artist"
但如果所谓的“艺术家”
is really out of the picture,
实在是出乎意料了，
then perhaps
they're worth something.
那么也许
它们是有价值的。
- Really?
- 真的吗？
[sobbing]
It's so complicated.
[抽泣]
太复杂了。
These are tears of joy, but
they're also tears of sadness
这是喜悦的泪水，但是
它们也是悲伤的泪水
for my good friend Squidward,
为了我的好朋友章鱼哥，
wherever he is.
无论他在哪里。
- Oh, there he is, Mr. Krabs.
- [grunts]
- 哦，他在那儿，蟹老板。
- [咕哝]
[ship whirring]
[船呼呼地响]
- Stay here and keep an eye
on me investments.
- 留在这里并留意
对我的投资。
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
Well, that was disgusting.
嗯，那太恶心了。
So who wants to talk about
my use of color
那么谁想谈论
我对颜色的运用
and brush stroke?
和笔触？
- [clears throat]
- [清喉咙]
Hm!
嗯！
- I have done everything I could
- 我已经做了我能做的一切
to get you away from here
safely.
让你离开这里
安全。
- Ah!
- Now you're messing
- 啊！
- 现在你搞砸了
with me money!
用我的钱！
- Dah!
- 啊！
- Run, Squidward, run!
- 快跑，章鱼哥，快跑！
- Hey!
- 嘿！
How about a little support here?
在这里提供一点支持怎么样？
- Run, Mr. Krabs, run!
- 快跑，蟹老板，快跑！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [quietly] But a little slower
than Squidward!
- [小声]但是慢一点
比章鱼哥！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
- [muffled shouting]
- It's your best friend,
- [低声喊叫]
- 这是你最好的朋友
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- Oh, get off of me!
- 哦，从我身上下来！
- I'll never get off of you,
Squidward.
-我永远不会离开你
章鱼哥。
Not until you're safe.
直到你安全为止。
- I'll never be safe!
- 我永远不会安全！
Not until my paintings are gone.
直到我的画消失了。
- No, Squidward!
- 不，章鱼哥！
You can't deprive the world
of your paintings!
你无法剥夺世界
你的画作！
- True, but it's better than
depriving the world of me.
- 确实如此，但比
剥夺了我的世界。
Hmm?
唔？
- [growls]
- Ah!
- [咆哮]
- 啊！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Come on, Squidward,
destroy those paintings
- 来吧，章鱼哥，
毁掉那些画
before Mr. Krabs gets back.
在蟹老板回来之前。
- [straining]
- [紧张]
I--I can't do it!
我——我做不到！
They're just too magnificent!
他们简直太伟大了！
- Hey, hey, hey!
- 嘿，嘿，嘿！
Get away from me paintings!
离我远点画画！
- Oh, I'm sorry, paintings,
but it's you or me!
- 哦，对不起，绘画，
但这是你还是我！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Yes. Yes!
- 是的。是的！
Now this is true art!
这才是真正的艺术！
- Wha--really?
- 啥——真的吗？
- So visceral, so dangerous.
- 如此本能，如此危险。
- Yes!
- 是的！
Feel my art!
感受我的艺术！
[laughing]
[笑]
- Leave me paintings alone,
you monster!
- 别管我的画，
你这个怪物！
- No!
- 不！
That was the most exhilarating
performance art
那是最激动人心的
行为艺术
I have ever seen!
我见过！
- Really?
- 真的吗？
So it must be worth millions!
那么它的价值一定是几百万！
Hey, out of me way!
嘿，别挡我的路！
[both laughing maniacally]
[两人都疯狂大笑]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
Mr. Krabs, uh, Squidward,
螃蟹先生，呃，章鱼哥，
I don't think
you should be doing that.
我不认为
你应该这样做。
- Oh, don't be so provincial,
SpongeBob.
-哦，别那么狭隘，
海绵宝宝。
- Yeah, stop trying
to censor our money!
- 是的，别再尝试了
审查我们的钱！
I mean, our art!
我的意思是，我们的艺术！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
There!
那里！
- Bravo!
- 太棒了！
Bravo! Bravo!
太棒了！太棒了！
[both grunting and yelling]
[咕哝和大喊]
- Ooh, boy, hee-hee!
- 哦，孩子，嘿嘿！
So, heh,
所以，呵呵，
how much you gonna give me
for all this?
你要给我多少钱
为了这一切？
[chuckles]
- Nothing!
[笑声]
- 没什么！
Performance art is about
the moment.
行为艺术是关于
那一刻。
You cannot put a price on it.
你无法为其定价。
- What?
Wait. Come back here,
- 什么？
等待。回到这里，
you double-crossing--
你这双重交叉——
- Doh! Mr. Krabs!
Squidward!
- 噢！蟹老板！
章鱼哥！
[strains]
[菌株]
- A-ha!
- 啊哈！
And that is how I acquired
this masterpiece.
这就是我如何获得
这部杰作。
- Ooh.
- Ahh.
- 哦。
- 啊。
- Bravo.
- 太棒了。
- I'm an artist.
- 我是一名艺术家。
- I'm rich.
- 我很有钱。
- And I helped.
[laughs]
- 我也帮忙了。
[笑]
[light string music]
[轻弦乐]
*